[
    {
        "question": "How long will these measures last for?",
        "answer": "(The latest measures will take effect from 22 July till 18 August 2021, and supersede measurers that were recently introduced.)\n",
        "start": [
            "22 July"
        ],
        "end": [
            "18 August 2021"
        ],
        "day_of": []
    },
    {
        "question": "These additional measures have impacted my business greatly. How is the Government supporting us?",
        "answer": "((i)\t<u>Enhanced Jobs Support Scheme (JSS) for affected sectors</u>\nIn view of the continued tightened safe management measures of various activities until mid-July 2021, the Government will extend the current enhancements to the JSS for affected sectors by 3 weeks (starting 21 June) before tapering it down to 10% for the subsequent 2 weeks. Please refer to the (https://www.moh.gov.sg/docs/librariesprovider5/pressroom/annex-b-mtf-18-jun.pdf) for more details.)\n\n((ii)  <u>Support to hawkers who are self-employed</u>\nTo support hawkers and coffeeshop stallholders who are self-employed, the Government will extend the subsidies for fees for table-cleaning and centralized dishwashing services, and will provide rental waivers, till mid-July 2021 for stallholders in centres managed by NEA or NEA-appointed operators.)\n\n((iii) <u>Food Delivery Booster Package and E-commerce Booster Package</u> \nESG reintroduced support measures to help affected F&B and retail businesses diversify their revenue channels and defray business costs of going online:)\n<ul>\n  <li>The Food Delivery Booster Package defrays part of food delivery costs, via food delivery platforms and third-party logistics partners, and will be available from 16 May to 15 July 2021.</li>\n  <li>The E-Commerce Booster Package provides up to 80% support for local retailers to get on-board local e-commerce platforms, and will be available from 16 May 2021 to 16 November 2021.</li>\n</ul>\n\n(In view of the tightened safe management measures until 18 August 2021, the Government will provide a support package to affected businesses and workers. More details will be announced at a later date.)\n",
        "start": [
            "16 May 2021",
            "16 May"
        ],
        "end": [
            "15 July 2021",
            "16 November 2021",
            "18 August 2021"
        ],
        "day_of": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Will there be updates on the GoBusiness portal for businesses, e.g. what are the permissible activities?",
        "answer": "(Please refer to the Safe Management Measures and guidelines stipulated in the sector-specific advisories on the GoBusiness portal.)\n",
        "start": [],
        "end": [],
        "day_of": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Am I allowed to operate at full capacity during this time?  Or must we limit work to specific hours or at certain manpower limits?",
        "answer": "(Employers must ensure that all employees who are able to work from home do so. For those that are unable to work from home, employers should stagger start times and allow flexible workplace hours. Employees should not be cross deployed to other worksites.)\n\n(Special attention should be paid to vulnerable employees (e.g. older workers, pregnant workers, and those with underlying medical conditions) to enable them to work from home. For these employees, you could consider temporarily redeploying them to another role within the company so that they are able to telecommute or work from home.)\n",
        "start": [],
        "end": [],
        "day_of": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Is there a minimum percentage or number of workers that employers must place on work-from-home-arrangements?",
        "answer": "(The objective of the requirements is to reduce physical interactions in the workplace in order to minimise spread of COVID-19. Employers should focus on providing the facilities necessary and directing every worker to work from home, as far as reasonably practicable. The proportion of employees that can do so will vary in different workplaces and sectors due to differing operational requirements.)\n\n(The onus is on employers to show that they have made a reasonable effort to facilitate working from home, including reviewing and transforming business processes through technology to support remote working e.g. e-payment, e-invoicing, e-signatures. In this regard, you may refer to MOMs (https://www.mom.gov.sg/-/media/mom/documents/covid-19/annex-a-resources-to-assist-companies.pdf?la=en&hash=A49779E587B330C7702C3A4B33401D85) that include technology solutions and grants available to assist companies.)\n",
        "start": [],
        "end": [],
        "day_of": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Are companies that are operating required to ensure that their employees work from home?",
        "answer": "(Work-from-home will continue to be the default at workplaces. Employers must provide the necessary facilities and direct their employees to work from home wherever possible.)\n\n(Work-from-home measures should be implemented in a sustainable manner that enables employees to maintain work-life harmony while continuing to meet business needs. The (https://www.mom.gov.sg/covid-19/tripartite-advisory-on-mental-well-being-at-workplaces) sets out practical guidance on measures that employers can adopt to support their employees mental well-being.)\n\n(A list of resources such as technology solutions and grants available to assist companies is available (https://www.mom.gov.sg/-/media/mom/documents/covid-19/annex-a-resources-to-assist-companies.pdf). Enforcement checks will be conducted and actions will be taken against businesses for non-compliance.)\n\n(For employees who need to return to the workplace, employers should continue to stagger start times of these employees and implement flexible working hours. Social gatherings at the workplace will not be allowed. Employees may have meal breaks at the workplace, but refrain from intermingling with their colleagues when their masks are taken off.)\n",
        "start": [],
        "end": [],
        "day_of": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Do I need to send my staff for regular testing?",
        "answer": "(All employees who work at settings with unmasked clients/patron, or where there is prolonged contact between individuals, are required to be placed on a regular Fast and Easy Tests (FET) regime using tests such as antigen rapid tests (ART). These include staff of:)\n\n(a.  Dine-in F&B establishments;\nb.  Personal care services (e.g. facial and nail services, spas/saunas, massage establishments, hairdressing, and make-up services); and\nc.  Gyms and fitness studios where clients are unmasked.)\n\n(The mandatory regular 14-day FET for staff at these settings will be progressively rolled out from 21 June 2021 and made mandatory from 15 July 2021.)\n\n(From 22 July through 18 August 2021, staff who work at settings with unmasked clients/patrons and were placed on mandatory FET regimes, will not be required to conduct FET if their business operations are suspended. For F&B establishments that choose to remain open for takeaway/delivery, they must continue to place their employees on the regular 14-day FET regime. Such regular FET will continue to be made free of charge during this period.)\n",
        "start": [
            "21 June 2021",
            "15 July 2021",
            "22 July"
        ],
        "end": [
            "18 August 2021"
        ],
        "day_of": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Why do I need to send my staff for regular testing?",
        "answer": "(Identified settings are of higher risks, as clients/patrons are unmasked while in close proximity to one another for prolonged periods of time. Employees who work at these settings would therefore need to undergo 14-day regular FET.)\n",
        "start": [],
        "end": [],
        "day_of": []
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the cost of getting the antigen rapid tests (ART)?",
        "answer": "(For establishments that are required to be placed on mandatory Fast and Easy Tests (FET) regime, the costs for the ART kits and training programmes for employees will be borne by the Government for the first 3 months, until 30 September 2021, during the initial roll-out.)\n\n(For those who wish to purchase the ART self-test kits, they are available at all major pharmacies in Singapore, and their retail prices range from $10 to $13 per test kit.)\n",
        "start": [],
        "end": [
            "30 September 2021"
        ],
        "day_of": []
    },
    {
        "question": "How do I organise/conduct Fast and Easy Tests (FET) for my employees?",
        "answer": "(FET for all dine-in F&B establishments will be conducted via Employer-Supervised Self Swab (ESSS) where employees will swab themselves under the supervision of a trained staff (supervisor). Supervision can be done either in-person or virtually.)\n\n(To support establishments in their efforts to get started on FET, the government has also set up training programmes that companies can leverage to train supervisors in their establishments to supervise ART self-swabs for their staff. These supervisor training programmes will be provided at no costs to these establishments for the next three months.)\n\n(Please refer to (https://www.enterprisesg.gov.sg/covid-19/fast-and-easy-testing) for more information on FET.)\n",
        "start": [],
        "end": [],
        "day_of": []
    },
    {
        "question": "I own a small business and am unable to organise the supervised self-swabs on my own. What should I do?",
        "answer": "(We encourage all businesses to conduct employer supervised self-swabs for their employees.)\n\n(However, for small businesses (e.g. hawkers or establishments with only 1 employee) who are unable to organise the supervised self-swabs on their own, the government will set up Quick Test Centres (QTCs) to support those who need to be tested. The first 2 QTCs at Tekka and Yishun will be operational from <strong>21 June 2021</strong>. More QTCs will be progressively set up.)\n\n(Businesses can refer to SFAs guide for onboarding for testing at Quick Test Centres (QTCs) instead (https://www.sfa.gov.sg/covid-19/mandatory-fast-and-easy-testing-(fet)-regime-for-all-outlet-employees-at-dine-in-f-b-establishments). Please refer to the section on How to onboard by Quick Test Centre? on the steps required.)\n",
        "start": [],
        "end": [],
        "day_of": []
    },
    {
        "question": "On the regular testing regime, is there a need to bring it to a shorter interval, instead of 14 days?",
        "answer": "(The Government will monitor the situation closely and if the need arises, the frequency may be increased.)\n",
        "start": [],
        "end": [],
        "day_of": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Can F&B establishments allow dine-in options?",
        "answer": "(From 22 July through 18 August 2021, all F&B establishments can only open for takeaway and/or delivery during this period. Dining-in is prohibited.)\n\n((i)\tWhile customers and delivery personnel are allowed to enter the premises of the F&B establishments for takeaway or delivery, they must leave the premises once they have picked up their orders.)\n\n((ii)\tDuring this period, F&B establishments should cancel all events and promotions that will generate crowding at their physical premises in a manner which is non-compliant with the SMMs.)\n\n(F&B establishments may serve as venues for marriage events and/or work-related events by third parties and are required to comply with the SMMs for these events. <strong>Food and drinks are not permitted to be served or consumed at solemnisations or work-related events. As a special provision, wedding receptions may be allowed to continue, up to a maximum of 100 attendees including the parties to the marriage. For the detailed SMM requirements for Marriage Solemnisations and Wedding Receptions, please refer to the GoBusiness portal.</strong>)\n",
        "start": [
            "22 July"
        ],
        "end": [
            "18 August 2021"
        ],
        "day_of": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Can establishments with Pub/Bar/Nightclub/Disco (PBND) licenses continue to provide takeaway and delivery services?",
        "answer": "(F&B establishments are allowed to continue food service operations, with the exception of (i) establishments with Pubs, Bars, Nightclubs, Discos and Karaoke SFA license categories or SSIC codes starting with 5613, and (ii) nightlife operators that were allowed to pivot to F&B operations as listed at (https://covid.gobusiness.gov.sg/permittedlist/) (operations suspended from 16 July through 30 July).)\n",
        "start": [
            "16 July"
        ],
        "end": [
            "30 July"
        ],
        "day_of": []
    },
    {
        "question": "My food establishment is located within an industrial building. Can it be allowed for dine-in during this period?",
        "answer": "(It can only serve takeaway and/or delivery orders only. No dine-in service is permitted. Customers are not permitted to consume any food or drinks on-site whilst waiting for the food to be prepared.)\n",
        "start": [],
        "end": [],
        "day_of": []
    },
    {
        "question": "My operating costs will increase due to the increased demand for takeaway containers. Can the Government help with costs?",
        "answer": "(To help mitigate costs, F&B establishments can encourage customers to bring their own takeaway containers. Some establishments have already started to do so by offering incentives such as a small discount.)\n",
        "start": [],
        "end": [],
        "day_of": []
    },
    {
        "question": "What if we run out of takeaway containers?",
        "answer": "(Singapore has sufficient stock of takeaway containers. Supply chains are open and new stocks are continuing to arrive in Singapore. Local suppliers are also ramping up their production capabilities to prepare to meet the increased demand.)\n\n(We encourage everyone to bring their own clean containers when buying food. This will not only help to reduce the amount of waste generated but also ease the demand on disposable containers. In turn, establishments should allow patrons to use their own reusable containers.)\n",
        "start": [],
        "end": [],
        "day_of": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Must a food delivery personnel wear a mask at all times?",
        "answer": "(Food delivery personnel must wear a mask at all times in the course of their work.)\n\n(The only two exceptions are when he/she is cycling to deliver food. A mask must be worn once he/she completes cycling.)\n",
        "start": [],
        "end": [],
        "day_of": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Can work-related events continue to be held at F&B establishments?",
        "answer": "(Work-related events (both non customer-facing and customer-facing) can be held within the workplace premises and third-party venues. Prevailing guidelines for the respective event venues will apply.)\n\n((i)\tNon customer-facing events (e.g. conferences, seminars):)\n\n(a.\tEvents held in F&B establishments are subject to a cap of 50 persons or a lower number, depending on venue capacity and safe distancing requirements.)\n\n(b.\tAt least one-metre spacing between individuals must be maintained at all times.)\n\n(c.\tFood and drinks are not allowed.)\n\n(d.\tPrevailing SMMs as indicated in MOMs Requirements for Safe Management Measures at the workplace continue to apply.)\n\n((ii)\tCustomer-facing events (e.g. product launches, marketing events):)\n\n(a.\tEvents organised by F&B establishments within their own F&B premises are subject to the maximum number of individuals that the venue may accommodate after safe distancing measures are adhered to.)\n\n(b.\tEvents organised by external parties at F&B establishments (where the F&B premises now function as a third-party venue) are subject to a cap of 50 persons (excluding service staff) or a lower number, depending on venue capacity and safe distancing requirements.)\n\n(c.\tFood and drinks are not allowed.)\n\n(d.\tEach group must be limited to a maximum of 2 persons, with at least one-metre spacing between groups.)\n\n(e.\tAll other prevailing workplace and venue SMMs must be adhered to.)\n\n(Such events are not permitted at public and common areas such as mall atriums, public transport nodes, HDB estates and common corridors.)\n",
        "start": [],
        "end": [],
        "day_of": []
    },
    {
        "question": "How can F&B establishments apply for earlier vaccination for their frontline workers?",
        "answer": "(F&B establishments interested in earlier vaccination can reach out to Restaurant Association of Singapore (RAS) at enquiry@ras.org.sg. RAS will work with F&B companies to obtain the necessary details to facilitate earlier vaccination.)\n",
        "start": [],
        "end": [],
        "day_of": []
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the next steps after applying for earlier vaccination? How long will F&B frontline workers have to wait to be vaccinated?",
        "answer": "(The Government recognises that staff of F&B dine-in establishments are involved in higher-risk activities and will facilitate earlier vaccination of individuals who work in these settings. Individuals will receive a SMS directly from MOH to book their appointment slots for vaccination, once there are available slots. We seek your understanding that SMSes will be sent progressively as vaccination appointment slots are made available as supplies arrive. Individuals are also encouraged to register under the national vaccination programme at http://www.vaccine.gov.sg if they are already in eligible age groups.)\n",
        "start": [],
        "end": [],
        "day_of": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Is the earlier vaccination open to all F&B frontline workers, including foreigners?",
        "answer": "(All staff of F&B dine-in establishments are eligible for earlier vaccination, regardless of nationality. Interested F&B establishments can reach out to Restaurant Association of Singapore (RAS) at enquiry@ras.org.sg for more details.)\n",
        "start": [],
        "end": [],
        "day_of": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Can I apply for earlier vaccination if I have already registered interest for vaccination previously?",
        "answer": "(If you have not received your vaccination booking registration code from MOH, you can still apply for earlier vaccination. To apply, you can reach out to Restaurant Association of Singapore (RAS) at enquiry@ras.org.sg for more details.)\n",
        "start": [],
        "end": [],
        "day_of": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Can F&B companies apply for priority vaccination for all employees, beyond frontline workers (staff who work at settings with unmasked clients/patrons, or where there is prolonged contact between individuals)?",
        "answer": "(The Government will facilitate earlier vaccination of all frontline staff who work at the physical outlets (including front-of-house and back-of-house operations) of dine-in F&B establishments as there is a higher risk for staff who work at settings with unmasked clients/patrons, or where there is prolonged contact between individuals. All other employees working in F&B companies (e.g. corporate staff, central kitchen staff) or non-dine in establishments (e.g. takeaway kiosks) will have to register under the national vaccination programme at http://www.vaccine.gov.sg.)\n",
        "start": [],
        "end": [],
        "day_of": []
    },
    {
        "question": "How can I find out more about the national vaccination programme? What are the side effects of vaccination?",
        "answer": "(For more details on the national vaccination programme, you can visit http://www.vaccine.gov.sg.)\n",
        "start": [],
        "end": [],
        "day_of": []
    },
    {
        "question": "I am a big establishment with a lot of outlets and employees. Will there be an alternative to self-collecting the kits?",
        "answer": "(To facilitate the collection of test kits, F&B establishments should submit full details at (https://go.gov.sg/fet-registration-food) by 5 July 2021.)\n\n(For large establishments with multiple outlets and employ a large group of employees, the logistics partner will reach out to them separately on the arrangement for point-to-point delivery following the submission of the form.)\n",
        "start": [],
        "end": [
            "5 July 2021"
        ],
        "day_of": []
    },
    {
        "question": "How do I create an account on SRS to upload the employees swab test results?",
        "answer": "(F&B establishments must submit their details at (https://go.gov.sg/fet-registration-food) for the set-up of their SRS accounts.)\n\n(Enterprises with multiple outlets are encouraged to submit a form for each outlet (or unique SFA license)<sup>2</sup>. The Point-of-Contact<sup>3</sup> (POC) indicated in the form must be the employee who will be responsible for both self-collection of the test kits, and the uploading of FET results to the SRS account.)\n\n(After the creation of the SRS account, the POC will need to upload the particulars of their supervisors. With the successful upload of their particulars, supervisors will be able to submit test results through the unique company SRS link.)\n\n(<sup>2</sup> For businesses with multiple outlets under the same UEN, you may submit your request to create multiple SRS company accounts under the same UEN. However, there must be a unique mobile number and email address used for each account. F&B establishments without a UEN can indicate their NRIC in the UEN field instead.<br>\n<sup>3</sup> Establishments are also able to nominate an alternate POC per outlet, if they wish to do so.)\n",
        "start": [],
        "end": [],
        "day_of": []
    },
    {
        "question": "When will the SRS be ready for upload of results?",
        "answer": "(The SRS is ready for companies to upload results. More details on the uploading of results to the SRS will be provided at www.enterprisesg.gov.sg/fast-easy-testing.)\n",
        "start": [],
        "end": [],
        "day_of": []
    },
    {
        "question": "How do I add entries for new supervisors/update supervisors details on the SRS?",
        "answer": "(Once the companys SRS account has been created, the POC may log into the account to upload supervisors details, as well as make edits subsequently. The upload of supervisors details would give them access to submit test results through the unique company SRS link.)\n",
        "start": [],
        "end": [],
        "day_of": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Is there a deadline for employers to key in the test results onto the SRS portal?",
        "answer": "(Establishments are required to upload the results of the outlet workers swab tests to the SRS on the same day as the tests are taken (within 24 hours).)\n\n(For Ag+ cases, the results must be submitted on the SRS within 30 mins from the time of the test.)\n",
        "start": [],
        "end": [],
        "day_of": []
    },
    {
        "question": "I understand that the F&B FET regime is mandatory from 15 July. I have received my ART test kits but am experiencing technical issues with the Swab Registration System (SRS) (e.g. unable to log into the system/ upload supervisors/ upload results). What should I do? Can I still continue to operate?",
        "answer": "(You can continue to operate. However, if you have received your ART test kits, you should proceed with the testing of your staff and keep a record of the results. Once the SRS system issues have been resolved, you will need to upload these backdated results into the system. Subsequently, all AG+ or Double Invalid test results will have to be uploaded onto SRS no later than 30 minutes after the ESSS for that specific staff is completed; whereas all other AG- test results needs to be logged onto SRS within 24 hours.)\n",
        "start": [],
        "end": [],
        "day_of": []
    }
]